Okay, they just close the door so I am police apologists I
amprinciple program manager on the visual studio client team
...here to talk to-you today about apache cordova
and a little bit more specifically about some of the things we've done for
both visual studio tooling and the windows platform for patchy cordova
as a little bit about my style I like to keep this interactive
so-if you have questions don't hesitate to interrupt me with questions
will give me a chance to take a little water break and, listen to the things that you care about make sure
...covering all this stuff you care about so don't hold your questions to the and just ask me also I'm
going-to from my demos switch between visual studio in the
command line if that scares you don't worry we'll get through it together and,
all my demos are going to be very simple things that we're going to use
to show concepts so that you guys can build on it I'm not a really complex
demo person because I think you can kind of tend to get lost in the so
...do simple stuff and of course you can take it to do more complicated
stuff as we go further...cover what cordova is how many of you already know
what cordova or phone gap is.
Bunch of you how many of you are already cordova developers.
Maybe fifteen percent
so great we're going to cover everything from what is creative
...to heidi's creative a for the.
Windows platform and for the ios and android platform so there's a little bit of something
for everybody will also cover how we builders apps and will
do demo obviously and then we'll talk about if cordova is the right
path for your app and what microsoft's path with cordova
is then we'll give you resources to go and learn more?
Clear that, you know, seven years ago
weirdness place where the big thing was the mobile web everybody
was building mobile websites and those were really great because you could get
him on every device in every browser and you could use your phone.
But, they had shortcomings he couldn't use offline you couldn't the use
the capabilities of the phones the devices very well and.
Is actually quite hard to monetize
a mobile app so mobile apps for a
sorry mobile web mobile apps kind of became the preferable thing you
could use the capabilities of the device itself you could do offline
and...could monetize these things but putting them in different stores and actually charging money for them
and users like the experience of being...app a lot better than they like the
experience of being in a browser and you can see that?
That developer users want to use those apps and that's
even increasing further than it was just a few years ago.
But, building all those apps can be really expensive and
it's clear that developers who write for mobile if you
ask them what their languages are that they use the
most common language that they talk about is html.
If you ask them what the primary languages the first thing that they use html
is right there behind java and objective see.
that kind of confluence of landscape positions means that something like
apache cordova that allows you to use html to write your mobile app
...gain traction fairly quickly
and today we see six percent of apps in-store specifically the google
...the ios store ability easing cordova and fourteen percent of apps
the categorize themselves as business apps you'd probably think of these
is line-of-business apps
the use cordova to the implemented the numbers beasts
behind the fire wall of app deployments behind firewall using into
...and other deployments like that are
hire and so.
With that landscape going to talk about what cordova is and how it works
cordova allows you to have a single code base is html?
Css and javascript host that inside the native web view
of the app container and show that inside
in app that is ios android and windows specific
...does all of this using in open-source framework.
you probably want to know how it gets to the device capabilities of each of the devices
that eases for instance the accelerometer or the camera or
barcode scanner it uses something called a plug-in api plugins are
implemented in the native code for each of the platforms.
And, then they're exposed to a javascript api.
And, that javascript api is common so if you're writing your html
and javascript to use these plugins...against one javascript
api any reach all of the platforms for that specific device capability.
We're going to focus a bunch today on
the windows platform but we're also going to talk about the ios...android platforms.
How does...developers
shown me how the pieces work when I create a cordova projects?
What I have...that project is my
html css and javascript and my assets and those are the things I
headed highlighted in yellow the things that are specific to the developer
...developer...brought to the game?
So, I might have brought some of my html javascript
and css and assets
from my website I might have written some of them just for my a creative
app these all our pieces of what gets built into the
...a project and
cordova ads platform code for those platforms that you said you'd like to support
and plug-in code for the plug-in that you said you'd like in your app and then
your configuration the things...said that you care about and some
of that is how my plug inness work in some of that is how
I'd like the pieces that are platform specific to
work so there are some settings that are particular to ios in those although not
configuration when I build that...over projects what I get our
projects that are specific to each of the platforms for windows I
...a visual studio project without html css javascript
and assets that are mine.
And, then the windows specific runtime and plug-in
code and the windows specific configuration that's going to look like
and epics manifest for windows in ios and up
...x code projects with again that same html css and javascript
...all of my assets and then the ios specific platform
plug-in configuration again
was android same thing and then when we build this we end up with
...native windows app and native ios app and native
android app the bills just straight into what you expect to be
...app and then you can take each of these
applications and submits into their respective stores?
Talk a little bit more about how the windows platform works because presumably
you guys are at least some of viewer windows developers are
...the windows platform has been on a journey.
I think of...zero as.
The place that are platform was
before about last summer we had a plethora of pieces of our
...platform there was a windows a platform and that was largely
...people were using it targeted windows a devices so
tablets and desktops for dub database so what we call the modern app
with the time.
Those also windows seven platform that was no longer
...and we...everybody was kind of discouraged from using it
...a windows phone seven-foot seven-point-five platform
that was deprecated and windows phone...was
the popular in market windows phone operating system and that was
really the platform that was very popular that most people were targeting
for cordova and that created silverlight app with the web view.
Starting in summer of twenty fourteen.
We did a bunch of work with the
cordova open-source community to create the windows platform.
The windows platform targeted windows eight-point one
...windows phone eight-point one windows phone
...windows eight-point one had a united model
...and that allowed us to really unite the cordova model as
And, it would created...a local context and you
could have all of your code can hosted in one place and it would you create actually
to binary because there was still...phone store and a windows
store but logically kind of thought of them is one thing because you had one project you
are working on windows found eight was still a version of windows phone that was in
market so it's still a very popular platform to target
the that continues to exist and the next phase what I think of as
...is after windows ten is finished in
rt m which is, you know, fairly soon?
We start the phase of windows of windows
universal, universal windows platform
and there's a single platform called windows that.
Can target those uw...apps and have some of
...single binary that will target?
Tablet desktop phone xbox.
Surface hub all of the great other devices
and the breadth of universal windows devices.
Because windows phone eight is still in market that platform
continues to exist and in accordance with how the
cordovathe...of a community works until that
platform has reached a very low usage that will continue to be
...then when it's very low usage we will deprecated with, you know, lots of
six months of warning to the community and then we encourage everybody...move over?
We can with the windows platform.
Target either deb a in local context or in
remote context for windows ten and the differences between
those two are in the security context
I'm not going to go deeply into the security context differences iness
...suffice to say that we think remote mode is probably the right thing for your
...app but there are times when local
mode might be the right thing so we've...that easily through
...configuration for cordova and you can switch that.
Inline script is one difference inline script works only in local
...not in
...so if you're in...script advocate you might want to switch.
And, we have been
...hard with the community to get windows tends creative a platform
ready to go and it's now available for public usage
...the apache cordova site as of the day
day-and-a-half ago will use it today and you'll see how you can use in your
app starting today and then as windows ten
...ends we will take contributions work with community and
...be rolled into the official windows platform for whatever.
The windows the cordova windows ten platform has
...several differences between it and the previous windows
platform support and other
the cordova platforms like ios
...one is part of the windows ten platform.
Design is that you can access
...rt from javascript this makes it really easy to
write platforms specific code for your...of app or if you're
an author that wants to write new plugins you can write them really easily
easing javascript or if you really like cplus-plus and csharp the can write
it in cplus-plus and csharp anything you can write a winner
t component and you can write a plug-in for cordova
in so easier to write...and it is for ios and for android.
Part of...database set of enhancements in windows ten is the
supported...the hosted content model this means if part
of your app say a pager to of your appis on
your website is part of your mobile website and you really just want to
point out there and tell your app just to get that page and make that
part of my app because I don't want to updated all the time and risa minute
to the store you can use the supported
her hosted content model directly within your...of app?
Embedded cordova is a pattern that allows
islands of cordova so imagine instead of a single web
view within your app you have several
little islands of web views each pointing to different parts of your
cordova app you can do the sign windows because of
a change in the security and when rt model and it's it can
be very powerful amazon for instances using this within their mobile app?
And, if you guys use of a and windows
...or windows eight-point one humane be familiar with some of
the security restrictions around safe html.
That kept you from using angular
and bootstrapping some of the other frameworks well.
That is no longer an issue we got rid of safety html and
now you can use all of the libraries you love within your windows html
app so that's a pretty big thing for windows and we'll make your lives
easier writing html...either through cordova or natively for windows.
We are as we are working with
the community to build the windows platform for
cordova we're also working to ensure that the top twenty-five
plugins have great support for the windows platform we
are mostly there but, we are working throughyou know,
bugs and issues with the new platform and each day we were getting kind of closer,
closer to filling out that matrix of all green for the top twenty five
...watches work in open-source and get closer and closer.
If you choose to use when js when js in the last
six months whence open-source and then released when js for
...that designed for
web use for mobile devices and you can choose to
use when js to build a great mobile interface you can she's not
too is a fully optional framework it offers for windows
devices great touch and keyboards support one of the shortcomings of
some of the you are libraries is that they don't have good
keyboard support and
...js...natively built this into their designed to have great
keywords support so that's an option and when js works really well with angular
and bootstrap and some of your other favorite frameworks?
So, how do I build a...of app?
Fantastic question my team the visual studio team
...a year-ago started on
a journey of building tools within visual studio to build
...of applications and we think
...first release...about a year-ago as an extension to
visual studio twenty thirteen in visual studio twenty fifteen we are now
in-box.
And, we are just an option you can check as you install.
And, were actually super excited about the work that we've done
for visual studio cordova you can use visual studio
to create coded debug all the things that you
would expect from visual studio on your
...of app and tell us sense we've got that
plugins can be are directly supported in the configuration...can you can
...can debug all of the kinds of things that you expect from visual
studio we support for cordova applications.
And, of course not just for windows for ios
and for android they may be asking ios.
Visual studio
...on windows how are you going to do that ios applications
can only be built on and for both technical and legal reasons
so while we can build a android apps for ios
apps what we have is a remote build agent you have your
...on a part of your network that runs
remote build agent we can build and the debug on that machine.
Visual studio gives you all the things you need to get started and this might not sound like a
big thing but when you start to incurred of a development
and you look at all of the pieces of open-source that you need to do that
it can be incredibly overwhelming the screenshot I took.
...get enough of them into get even halfway down the list of all of the
open-source tools that you need to get started on
...a development you can see I got to
...emulator for android so not even not even
halfway through the alphabet these pieces apache
...ripple come from the community but
she need them all and getting them all on your machine with the right versions that
work together that aren't broken that don't have security issues is
huge it's a really big issue one of the things that visual studio
does is brings them all down
for you in one single install and then we maintain them
...if for instance
get has a security issue like it did two months ago we
push down to your machine the next time you open your projects...new version of get
that we verified with this stack of tools if something gets
an installed and the tool chain isn't going to work anymore we
checked before next build and we reinstall the pieces
that you need to make sure that your build is going to work so
we do that not just when you install but an ongoing basis when
you build and that lies stream of checking your dependencies is one of our
big value props for visual studio that we think we can help you with.
Of course as part of the cordova community
were contributing everything we do in
open-source back to that community to make it better for all targets
not just for our visual studio developers because as part of
an open-source community that's what you do you help each other
...when you six-something you send a polar...back
to that community we have five or seven contributors to
cordova on the team and then we contribute back to other projects.
You can see some of the examples of things that we've already contributed I'm not going to read
them all but significant things that we spent a lot of time making
sure work well not just for our tools but for
...tools for people who don't want a tool set they want to just pull the pieces
together themselves and of course for anything for windows that we can do to
...windows development work more smoothly with apache whatever
we ensure that we're doing the right things for the community and contributing this back.
Great so show me let's see what it looks like.
As I switch over if anybody has questions so little hard
...dasi out yet can you actually can get a microphone so we can capture.
Ask...no repeat.
Yeah, absolutely the question is what versions of...visual studio
have these tools the visual studio community addition does have a
...cordova tools and is a full version visual
...of they will be right there in the install and you can check
...and use them visual studio code today does not have support
for apache...the development in the future will see
the visual studio code is a pretty new project so...can doing, you know,
working...the stack for that?
All right so let's give it a spin I have visual studio
and this is installed on.
Last week's build of...ten that you guys can all
down the today we're going to create a new project just as you would think we would using visual
...a new project template.
We'll call this location app I'm going to build a really simple location app.
The using
our geo location module inside this laptop.
And, you may say.
Geo location big deal you...do that in html five.
It's a fair point you...going to be using the cordova a plug-in for it
I could have used another plug-in I just this one was very simple and,
you guys could follow it as we think about
cordova was set of plugins that we would think of
as core like geo location like.
The camera and web can those api
service a model for what should move from cordova
into html five so we try to
designers api in a way that they can move smoothly from cordova
to html five often with no api changes and that is already happened for
geo location and for some of the other api as like camera...plug-in
continue to exist so for some amount of time you kind of have both.
But, we'll build a simple location app using the location the
geo location plug-in and I'm going to use angular.
For this app but before we get to coding.
Because our new windows platform.
Uses the new version of the
cordova command line interface I'm going to ask for the new version of the
creative a command line interface and then.
To ensure I have it I
build my visual studio does a says you ask for
...command line interface five data so I'm going to check your machine make sure that you
have it downloaded if you don't and build great we now have it.
I'm going to switch over to the command line and let's add a few things to the project.
The first is that we're going to add the platform
for windows the new platform so we'll do that using creative
a platform and windows in the
future all you need to do is could...a platform ad windows and further
...actually able to do this from visual studio because
our platform for windows is changing and it's not
excepted into the mainline branch yet until it's done.
We need to point to the right...of for the windows
...platform...prototype so I'm going to given address
...platform ad windows at.
...already.
But, this is going to do is it's going to go out to where this platform
lives and pull it down using and pm an added to my projects?
Fantastic it's always good when you have internet access for your demos and now because I
want to use a angular in my app let's go and add angular as well.
...to go into where my source code for this project is
...look at this in more depth later but we're going to
in can install.
Angular.
Grates and...put that into our project.
Let's take a look at what we have in solution explore in this project.
We have on the right side here is all the files the make-up my...
project we talked about configuration we already looked at the configuration manager
once please it again this is where I manage all the things for each
of my platforms plus the platform agnostic
settings the code from my app is right here in deb.
And, index html is the html home
planning page for my app.
And, then in scripts I have...js file.
And, let's go into.
Will add a little bit of code?
I need to reference my a.
Angular app a angular source kids so
...add a reference to.
...pull out some of the default...
And, I'm going to add a little bit of html.
So, that you all don't have to watch type I'm horrible at talking and typing at
the same time inside this did what we have is very simple
uyvy with a button that says go get my location and
...that says my location is lat long.
What we're pointing to is an angular controller you can see the engine
control interactive and now I need to go write that angular
controller all open up my index file and because
I'm using angular I'm going to pass into my function
...dot angular?
If you haven't seen this can before don't worry it's fairly.
Simple.
Once we get that angular object we need to...
Now we need our directive.
What's the scheck at presuming.
Okay, what I pasted in here is a very simple
controller that goes and gets location calls
...get location method that wethat we called in our html?
And, it uses navigator
...dot get current position this is the plug-in for geo location
and is if you've used html you'll notice
that it looks a lot like the
api for a camera for other types of
device capabilities for html five as I mentioned that by design
and then I'm going to pass into get current position the method for
on location found that's my a...call back when the location is found
I can grab my latin long put into my scope that goes back into my html?
Because we're using this...location plug-in we need to add to our
project going to bring up the configure designer.
And, go to plugins.
One of the things visual studio does is it provides a list of the plugins that we've tested and
no work together well you can see that these
...are all the core plugins and straight from here you can add them to your projects.
I am going to go to geo location.
And, add that plug into my projects and you can see it
pop-up in plugins...location right there.
And, now we can actually run
and this thing let's switch to windows any cpu.
And, we'll run it on a local machine.
And, what you see is a universal windows at like you kind of expected three
...and it's got that your control instead of
the charms thing and when I click find my location?
I get asked by the windows security system.
Do I want to let this app access my
geo location in my app as you would with any other app that's
needed to windows I can say yes and then it'll asynchronous
...come back with my location hopefully
...go and it's on the wi-fi...I...slowed to a to give me back
a location and because this is running locally?
Through visual studio I can actually do all of the debugging
kinds of things that you would expect so I can actually come into body and I
can say let's give body and new inline style of back
color.
And, we'll give it...colorless a orange.
And, it changes...dynamically
...so this is pretty powerful I can debug this rate here without going out
to the device or if I have a device tethered I can actually debug to my
device that's tethered and you're thinking...windows of course you can we can also
...as a ripple
as a built for android apps using.
The ripple emulator and the ripple emulator comes up in chrome simulates says you guys
might gas the android environment that's
of benign.
Exception with the pass it and then I can find my location
and again I can debugging change background color for instance.
So, this is pretty powerful I can change
...chrome around it and I'll change
...the resolution in the dimensions and things like that.
I can do most of my development straight from visual studio
without ever having to kind of leave the nicecomforting
...environment that.
Allows visual studio developers to be pretty productive using
intel sense of the...however a lot of my final
...stuff is going to have to be on the device because you guys have probably a set of devices that you care
about a lot so we can also tether and do the same kinds of things?
So, let's shut this down.
let's take a little bit deeper look into what it is that we've created.
Go back into.
The command line and.
Look, at the platforms that we.
Added.
And, we see android and windows and windows any cpu and we can
actually ad here the creative a platform and
...for instance.
Just like we added windows...nagging and ios
folder on platforms and we can see it pop-up here are sheila
trick early like these show all files in the solution explore
to see everything in the platforms directory...now we see others platforms.
If we expand windows.
We see a bunch of cia is...js project files...project files
are for the platforms that we're building...and creative app...windows ten
...is how we build the windows ten app as you guys might
If we expand out the ios
...we get is an x code project you can take this project from access
...right here and actually build it using x code on your
act which is how we...remote build agent for ios.
So, let's open it up now...stan.
We'll go into platforms.
Windows.
The windows ten js project.
...operation never need to do this I'm just showing you what it is we build so that you guys
have a better understanding of how we create our...of
...apps and kind of all the pieces that go into it but you will never
need to worry about the project file for your windows
...your windows cordova app but it's fun to look around
so now instead of what we put into
...dot xml.
Your settings are in the app manifests.
We added the geo location so we have a device capability
for location that came in when we added the plug-in for geo location.
We...js for a little bit of our initialization code under
www is are index html that we wrote.
And, just...pretty this is actually a project that you could do anything you want with
just like any other windows project we can actually
deployed this...device.
And, I have here.
Switch...minute.
Unlocking I have here engineering device for windows ten phone.
To play to the device in all cross our fingers.
It takes a minute for these engineering devices to connect.
Wake-up.
You won't need to deploy from the windows
project you...do this from the cordova project.
That's true and might time.
I'm just showing you that this model has the our to let you actually take
control of that generated project but of course you're going to want
to stay in your cordova project.
Let's see if I actually.
...us one more try none.
...move on.
...so app came up.
I can click find my location and again windows...am I going to let
this app actually access my location I'll say yes and in a minute
it'll come up with my location and were running a little bit long-time so I
want use divider but I could go in...change the
background color of this app as it's running directly from visual studio.
So, great let's switch back.
Let's talk about what you guys need to be able to do development using visual studio windows,
windows...developer previous was released yesterday and if you're going to develop for windows
send me windows...and the visual studio
twenty fifteen rc is also public the...
rc is has all the...greatest bits for cordova development you can choose to the
creative a development also on visual studio twenty thirteen and download the
extension?
Either way
...the windows ten cordova platform repo ...yes.
The question is it and...of the visual studio cordova
...the tools on twenty...on visual studio twenty thirteen
...that is I believe that has...right.
Visual city twenty thirteen cordova tours.
If I can...it's...fully supported.
And, if you're going to use the new windows...go ahead.
They do actually lets.
...his question is do my html
and javascript files get bundled with the application they do they become part of
the application that is built into the web view that you deploy and then
you submit to the apple storm.
If you the change your javascript coder your html code
you rebuild your app and then you re submit to store there is
an emerging pattern of being able to use hosted content what
I think you're kind of getting at is I want real change my code without
risa meaning me to the store and that's the hosted app content
model the cordova community is building patterns around this and
we're working on ways to support well in the visual studio
...a tool set so yes, you can do this today it's a little bit
more work but ...it's pretty cool that you can kind of dynamically update your app that's running.
So, it's really hard...the...
So,...holding up tablet I think it's an android tablet...
Okay, would you tether this yes the best way to do that is to
connected device typically very a usb cable and then you
can deploy to the device and you can debug directly on the device and you
can change things as...continue essentially as
...running and see how renders on that device you also have the
option of using and emulator to run completely
on the local machine to kind of
savy that time of tether in your device and, going back and forth?
Is there a way to...crosswalk is?
One of the process of html is that html as rendered on a variety
of different rendering engines and those rendering engines rather
render things differently crosswalk is a model that takes web
kit and packages it up as part of your app and then
uses just the crosswalk html rendering engine so, you know,
across all platforms that it's rendering exactly the same he's asking if there's tooling
...video for
crosswalk there isn't specific tooling in visual studio for crosswalk
but you can take your crosswalk platform pieces and use
them inside a and app just
...you would in any other app and use it in visual studio tools.
The through the...visual studios...
Samoa.
I think you're asking two questions
one is how do we manage dependencies on an ongoing basis.
Where they end up in the file system they end up in the file system where the
...tools want to be install too so, we?
I think right now they all go by default into the visual studio path
that you've chosen so when you install you pick a visual studio drive
...it gets installed...
Yeah, so, we test all these and make sure that we're not running into
...path issues we do know that path issues can be an issue
and for what we install right now we haven't had
a issues that...precluded down to users.
we have a we are working on aasl lie to make sure that are commend linear
faces really good and that's kind of part of what we're considering we should talk specifically
about all the passing issues that you have questions on and, we can address...
And, then so, you'll go to the apache repo for
the to in progress platform.
Prototypes that we have for windows and then we just published
today a blog in visual studio blog with the step-by-step on how to use this
you can go and try it out for yourself.
Analogy seen all about
...the next natural question is window
...use cordova I have this decision between building
accord of app in building native apps when do I do one of the other.
If you want to build and app
and use your web skills your developers that
really love html and all of your assets from the web.
...make a lot of sense for you if you want that one code base
advantage across all of your devices in your targeting at least two
platforms maybe three platforms heard of a starts to give you wins.
And, if you have javascript
libraries like angular like bootstrap that you have a bunch of invested knowledge
and you really want to use this is going to be hard to use this from a
native apps occured of a gives you that ability use them.
If you have.
Apps that are.
Gaming apps for instance where performance is
v first concern for your app the
...you move up the stack for any set of frameworks the more performances
...to...this is true of cordova it's true of.
Html in general it's true of any high-level stacks so if you're
thinking,
you know, I really need every last the processor cycle
cordova might not be the right choice for your app that for
attentive apps that are kind of anything from casual gaming to
...line-of-business apps where performance is not your first
concern that maybe something a little bit
further down the line...of...something you would want to consider if you want.
Apps that do different things and act differently and
looked differently across different,
different platforms...of obviously is not what-you want-to do because you don't want that quote
base you want your ios app to behave differently from your android app
so you would probably write native ios apps
and native android apps if you super-duper love java and
objective see and the direct...then you probably want to
retinas so go ahead and write native apps and if you
find yourself saying well actually what I love is example and csharp.
I would encourage you to take a look at cameron because amr analyze you to do
cross platform apps using...csharp and sample and with a
lot of the benefits of cordova with a different programming language.
And, if you really,
really have deep integration with the platform things like
the direct
...rendering pipeline if you're doing shatters for instance crevices probably not the way, you know,
...you need to talk directly to the operating system sagan need to go native.
He is really serious...of us here microsoft
why do you care well we want developers to have the very
best experience both in visual studio but also
for windows we know that people want to build creative apps so we...be
greater windows and we want all developers to come to visual studio so visual
studios been investing in this for a year-and-a-half we've been working really closely with
us g team and the
...has been investing in cordova for longer they've they were
very closely tied to the original windows eight in windows platforms.
And, have been great partners for visual studio in doing all the things we want
to do to make the creative a platform for windows even better we are working on
feature investments for visual studio things like improve command
line interfaces and interop with other command lines for cordova and
...build path for ios?
And, more app services
for things like the three sixty five and app
insights many of these you can do today we want to make them even smoother for you to build to build.
things that windows have done over the last year so within windows
tends to make the creative a platform even better the hosted app
content model that we talked about where you can kind of dynamically update your
content is something that we worked really hard in partnership with os...
any...web...support so that in multiple web
views you can actually access...rt was a big thing for os
...and they really did it so that we could do the
court ofapp model well we re design security model so that things
like html or no longer an issue for developers
and then they also are contributing their code back to os...visual studios.
We are really excited to have sales forces
a partner building on top of the windows ten platform today you guys probably saw
in the keynote that sales forces building
...force one as...that for windows ten some of their
cordova investments allow their sales
first sdk to run across windows ten and android
...and the ios using cordova and they've been great plot the
partners in helping us...out some of the issues and,being just general early adopters.
One of the things we hear a lot is that building your uri
for across platform is difficult there are
libraries out there that help bridge this specifically for cordova
applications.
And, on the racy unseen ui and on the left uci
enc both of those libraries have created templates for new
projects which you can get within the visual
studio gallery today to help you get started using those controls that
rendell in a platform specific way on each of the apps...each
...platforms so that dror control for instance that you see on the right in
the ios simulator is a very popular pattern that is meant to look like
the ios pattern and will render a little bit differently on android similarly for
...so encourage if you want to use those
libraries to use the visual studio templates in the gallery?
More resources the apache...a website has a
...of documentation on how cordova works.
And, the visual studio cordova site has a lot of documentation on how you
can use it within visual studio
our blog for visual studio has close to
weekly updates on things that we're doing with cordova tooling
...a great resource for how to use and news windows ten
...center for anything that is windows specific the
development and information is where you still go you
guys have probably been to windows...before...learn
...of a youtube videos is something we have a series of seven videos on youtube
...help you put together cordova app on visual studio sessions
a build yes I know wednesday at eleven thirty is coming
gone but if you guys go online all of the sessions are going to
be online and one of my colleagues hat did an overview
on of different types of mobile development across
platforms so included ...cplus-plus as well tomorrow my
colleague brian is doing a talk specifically on the performance of
...apps showing a lot of numbers and a lot of research that
we've done on how...apps...perform across...encourage you to check
that that's a really great talk and you can always current financial languages
booth some of the languages because I'm also a
take script kristen setup and current find me and ask me stuff.
And, that's it you guys have questions.
I'd love to hear them and of course evaluating.
Thanks every I know...so enjoy the party.